Finding aid to the Mary Daly papers SSC.MS.00637
Sophia Smith Collection
Mary Daly papers
1928-2013
Sophia Smith Collection
Daly, Mary, 1928-2010
SSC.MS.00637
0.002 Gigabytes (7 digital files)
59.53 linear feet (75 containers)
Mary Daly (1928-2010) was a radical feminist theologian, author, lecturer, and professor of religious and women's studies. This collection includes records of her personal and professional life. Of particular interest are Daly's fight with Boston College, her writing process, and her argument with Audre Lorde.
Conditions Governing Access
This collection is open for use without restriction beyond the standard terms and conditions of Smith College Special Collections.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Mary Daly started donating her papers to the Sophia Smith Collection in 2009. This collection is comprised of six separate accessions received from Daly and her estate in 2009-2010, and one received in 2012: 09S-13, 09S-72, 10S-17, 10S-32, 10S-48, 10S-81, 12S-38.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged into four series: Professional materials, Writings, Correspondence, and Personal records. Series are arranged roughly in the order they arrived at the archive. Oversize, AV, digital, ephemera, and books appear at the end of each series.
Biographical Note
Mary Daly, a radical feminist theologian who referred to herself as a Positively Revolting Hag, was born in Schnectady, New York, in 1928, the only child of a homemaker mother and a traveling salesman father. She was raised Catholic and attended Catholic schools. Early in her childhood, Daly had mystical experiences in which she felt the presence of divinity in nature.
She received a BA in English from the College of St. Rose in Albany, NY in 1950; an MA from Catholic University of America in 1952; and a Ph.D. in Religion from the School of Sacred Theology, St. Mary's, Notre Dame, in 1954. Unable to find a school in America that would allow a woman to obtain a"canonical" Doctorate in Sacred Theology, she went to Fribourg, Switzerland, where the education was state-controlled and could not legally exclude women. There she received a Doctorate in Theology and a Ph.D. in Philosophy as well as a Licentiate in Sacred Theology.
When she returned to the United States in 1966, she took a tenure track position at Boston College. Her first book, The Church and the Second Sex (1968) was influenced by a visit to Rome during Vatican II. The book, called a "searing expose of Christian misogyny, especially in the Catholic Church," critiqued the patriarchal structure of the Catholic Church and its detrimental effect on shaping women's lives and self-image. The book established Daly as a radical feminist theologian and a powerful voice of dissension, and Boston College fired her soon after its publication. However, amidst student protests and public outcry, Daly was reinstated and given tenure.
She went on to teach at Boston College for thirty-three years and published seven more books: Gyn/Ecology: The Metaethics of Radical Feminism (1978), Pure Lust: Elemental Feminist Philosophy (1984), Beyond God the Father (1985), Webster's First New Intergaliactic Wickedary of the English Language (with Jane Caputi; 1987), Outercourse (1992), Quintessence (1998), and Amazon Grace (2006).
Daly regularly toured nationally and internationally, lecturing, speaking and teaching at over three hundred college and universities. In addition to her own work, Daly was connected to many other feminist scholars, theologians and radicals of her day including Adrienne Rich, Diana Davies, Andrea Dworkin, Artemis March, Sonia Johnson, Jane Caputi, Merlin Stone, Janice Raymond, Robin Morgan, Julia Penelope, Gloria Steinem, Roseanne Barr, Pauli Murray, Linda Barufaldi, and Emily Culpepper. Daly retired from Boston College in 1999, although she claimed she was forced to do so. She died in Gardner, Massachusetts in January 2010.
Scope and Contents
This collection consists of the personal and professional papers of Mary Daly. It includes correspondence, including fan mail; drafts and galleys of many of Daly's books; financial information; research files and subject files (on topics including students, colleagues and public figures); documents pertaining to legal disputes with Boston College in 1969 and 1999; personal files re: health, pets, automotive, investments, medical, etc.; books; and teaching materials, including course outlines, syllabi, and confidential student records. Of particular interest are Daly's fight with Boston College, her writing process, and her argument with Audre Lorde.
Acronyms:
AAR- American Academy of Religion
AAUW- American Association of University Women
AG- Amazon Grace
BC- Boston College
BGTF- Beyond God the Father
G/E- Gyn/Ecology
MS- Manuscript
NWSA- National Women's Studies Association
OC- Outercourse
SCP- Spiritual Counterfeits Project
WEAL- Women Equity Action League
WONAAC- Women's National Abortion Action Coalition
Separated Materials
In 2019, student grades and evaluations were removed from the collection and destroyed. Duplicate materials were removed, and books not written by Daly were weeded out. A full list of the books in Daly's library can be found in Series IV. AV materials - duplicates and audio/video cassettes not pertaining to Daly were also removed. For a full list of these, please see Special Collections staff.
Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
This collection contains materials received from the donor in digital form that are not currently available online. Please consult with Special Collections staff to request access to this digital content.
Catholic Church -- United States -- History; Catholic women -- Biography -- Sources; Feminism -- United States; Feminist spirituality -- History -- Sources; Feminist theology -- United States -- History -- Sources; Feminists -- Massachusetts; Goddess religion -- History -- 20th century -- Sources; Lesbian activists -- United States -- Biography -- Sources; Lesbian feminism -- United States -- History -- Sources; Lesbians -- Massachusetts -- Biography -- Sources; Religions -- Study and teaching -- History -- Sources; Spirituality -- United States -- History -- 20th century -- Sources; Universities and colleges -- Massachusetts -- History -- Sources; Women authors, American -- 20th century -- Biography -- Sources; Women college teachers -- United States -- History -- Sources; Women radicals -- United States -- History -- 20th century -- Sources; Women in Christianity; Women in the Catholic Church -- United States -- History -- Sources; Women's rights -- Religious aspects -- Catholic Church; Women's studies -- History -- 20th century; Women and religion -- History -- Sources; Boston College -- Faculty; Rich, Adrienne; Caputo, Jane; Davies, Diana; Dworkin, Andrea, 1946-2005; Johnson, Sonia; Morgan, Robin; Stone, Merlin; articles; clippings; Contracts; correspondence; Financial records; Fliers; Galley proofs; Hearings; Legal documents; Mailing lists; Manuscripts; Medical records; Newsletters; Newspapers; Notes; Periodicals; Publicity; Research; Resumes; Scripts; syllabi; Electronic records; Daly, Mary, 1928-2010; MacRae, Jean E.; Hunt, Mary E.; Kelly, Nancy; Barufaldi, Linda; MacRae, Jean E.; Hunt, Mary E.; Kelly, Nancy; Barufaldi, Linda; Daly, Mary, 1928-2010
- SERIES I. Professional, 1954-2011; 15.418 linear feet (19 containers)
  Scope and Contents
  This series contains the professional records of Daly. Included in this series are course materials spanning much of Daly's career at Boston College, including syllabi and class notes, course evaluations and correspondence with current and former students, including Janice Raymond, later author of the controversial The Transsexual Empire. This series also includes legal documents, letters of support, clippings from the press, and fundraising documents related to Daly's "harassment" by Boston College and the Center for Individual Rights regarding her application for tenure and her refusal to teach male and female students together. Researchers can also find flyers, schedules and some correspondence related to Daly's speaking engagements and conferences. More correspondence about Boston College disputes and speaking engagements can be found in the correspondence series. Records related to Daly's writing career and book tours can be found in writings.
  - Th. 502, Intro to Feminist Ethics, 1997 (Box 1)
  - Fribourg - Phil. of God, 1965-1966 (Box 1)
  - Fribourg - Metaphysics - Villa + LeSalle (Box 1)
  - BC Faculty Handbook, 1995 (Box 1)
  - BC Fall/Spring, 1997-1998 (Box 1)
  - Mythic Patterns of Patriarchy II - Fall, 1993 (Box 1)
  - BC Grades, Spring, 1998 (Box 1)
  - Feminist Ethics I, Th. 553 (Box 1)
  - BC Class Rosters/Grades, 1997-1998 (Box 1)
  - Curriculum Vitae, 1988-1990 (Box 1)
  - Feminist Ethics II, Th. 554, 1989 (Box 1)
  - Report on Matilda Joslyn Gage + Mary Daly (Box 1)
  - Hye-sook Hwang, Helen, 2007 (Box 1)
  - Hwang, Helen Hye-sook, Letters of Recommendations (REMOVED) (Box 1)
  - Bohm, David (Box 1)
  - Biographical Information (Box 1)
  - Antioch College, 1988-1989 (Box 1)
  - St. Sebastian School Logo, 2007 (Box 1)
  - Application to Full Professorship, Boston College, 1988-1989 (Box 1)
  - Notebook (Box 1)
  - C. V., 1999 (Box 1)
  - Miscellaneous - documents found loose in box JR11 (Box 1)
  - St. Petersburg, FL. (Esther M), 1998 (Box 1)
  - SW Missouri Slate March 12, 2000 (Box 1)
  - Speaking Invitations Rev'd Sept. - Oct., 2001 (Box 1)
  - Kalitzkus, Sabine, 1998 (Box 1)
  - Roussos, Katherine (Box 1)
  - NAWCHE, 2000 (Box 1)
  - NAWCHE, 1999-2000 (Box 2)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 1)
  - BC Settlement Docs, 2001 (Box 1)
  - Gretchen Van Ness Billing and Correspondence, 2001 (Box 1)
  - Mary Daly Defense Fund Letter, 2000-2001 (Box 1)
  - Smeal, Eleanor, 2000 (Box 1)
  - Catholics for a Free Choice and Feminist Majority, 2000 (Box 1)
  - Hospital Insurance Accident Florida HPHC, 2000 (Box 1)
  - CIR Info, 1999 (Box 1)
  - GW University, DC, 2001 (Box 1)
  - UC EQ, 2000 (Box 1)
  - Eviction, 1999 (Box 1)
  - Letters of Support, 1998 (Box 1)
  - Emory U Women in Center, 2002 (Box 1)
  - Faculty Handbook, Bylaws, Retirement Planning, Medical/Dental, 1995-1998 (Box 1)
  - Center for Individual RIghts, 1998-2001 (Box 1)
  - Gretchen-- Beneficiary, 2000 (Box 1)
  - BC Settlement Agreement, 2001 (Box 1)
  - Mail Forwarded from BC, 2001 (Box 1)
  - Final Settlement with GVN via E. Wolfe, 2001 (Box 1)
  - Daly to Van Ness Letter, 2001 (Box 1)
  - Gyn/Ecology Book Order, 1999 (Box 1)
  - BC "Stuff" Parking and Inter Library Loan and Emily, 1997 (Box 1)
  - CVs, 1998 (Box 1)
  - BC Courses, 1992-1993 (Box 1)
  - The Mary Daly Defense Fund Letters, 1999 (Box 2)
  - Faculty Contracts and Yearly Notices of Salary Increments, 1966-1983 (Box 1)
  - BC and CIR Attack: Student Letters, 1999 (Box 1)
  - BC Leaves of Absence, 1971-1996 (Box 1)
  - BC Book Orders, 1999 (Box 1)
  - Mailing Lists, 1998-1999 (Box 1)
  - TH 554 FE, 1998 (Box 1)
  - Intro to Feminist Ethics Th. 302, 1992-1998 (Box 1)
  - Mythic Patterns, 1994 (Box 1)
  - Timelines for Characters in 'Canny Comments' (Box 1)
  - TH 302, 1998 (Box 1)
  - FE II, 1994 (Box 1)
  - BC Fall Courses TH 553, 1998 (Box 1)
  - Miscellaneous Documents, 1997-2001 (Box 2)
  - Potential Donors, 1997 (Box 2)
  - Defense Fund Contacts (Box 2)
  - Letter to Leahy Letters to M.D. re: case, 1999-2000 (Box 2)
  - Letters Received, 1999-2000 (Box 2)
  - Feminism II, 1989 (Box 2)
  - Beacon Press, 2000 (Box 2)
  - Mary Daly Defense Fund Letters, 1999 (Box 2)
  - Loose papers from Box JR14 (Box 2)
  - Journals and datebooks, 1976-2008 (Box 2)
  - Medora Feehan Fund, 1959-1973 (Box 2)
  - Attacks, 1973 (Box 2)
  - Publications / Outlines of Speeches Given, 1971 (Box 2)
  - BC Harassment, 1979-1980 (Box 3)
  - Outlines of Lectures / Portland, Chattanooga [?], etc. Abortion Talks, 1969 (Box 3)
  - Firing - Daly, 1969 (Box 3)
  - Chronology of Application for Full Professorship - Diary + Dossier Contents, 1988 (Box 3)
  - Applications for Full Professorship, 1988 (Box 3)
  - Syllabi for Mythic Patterns of Patriarchy (Box 3)
  - Crone-ology / Jan Histon / Harassment, 1966-1979 (Box 3)
  - Emily Culpepper (Box 3)
  - Application for Promotion to Full Professorship, 1988 (Box 3)
  - Th. 566 Mythic Patterns of Patriarchy Spring, 1989 (Box 3)
  - BC Course Evaluations Fall, 1973 (Box 3)
  - Audre Lorde, 1979 (Box 3)
  - Mary Daly Defense Fund, 2000 (Box 3)
  - BC "Annual Update" Samples, 1998 (Box 3)
  - The Observer - Separation of Women and Men / Correspondence with Barth and Monan, 1989 (Box 3)
  - M. Kauffmann Pictures (Box 3)
  - BC Salary Increment, 1986-1987 (Box 3)
  - Addendum on Teaching Women and Men (extra copies) (Box 3)
  - Full Professorship Application / Syllabi, Box Contents (Box 3)
  - Extra Evaluation Forms (Box 3)
  - Messing, Ellen and letters re: full professorship (Box 3)
  - Letters, Manon, 1988 (Box 3)
  - Rodgers, Liz, 1989 (Box 3)
  - BC Contract, 1969 (Box 3)
  - BC Harassment AAR, 1985 (Box 3)
  - BC Increment Report & BC Annual Report, 1984-1988 (Box 3)
  - BC Salary Increment, 1984 (Box 3)
  - Homans, Bill and Ann Sliver, 1989 (Box 3)
  - BC Ads Mary Daly's Name, 1984-1989 (Box 3)
  - "Course Reduction" Brown, Stephen Chair of Theology Dept., 1989 (Box 3)
  - History: Sample Yearly Reports and Departmental Evaluations for Salary, 1984-1988 (Box 3)
  - Correspondence, 1982-1983 (Box 3)
  - Student/Course Evaluations, 1984-1988 (Box 3)
  - Full Professorship Application Box Contents (Box 3)
  - Envelopes, 1988 (Box 3)
  - Brown, Stephen, 1989 (Box 3)
  - BC Propaganda, 1989 (Box 3)
  - Grievance Committee, 1989 (Box 3)
  - Application for Promotion, 1988 (Box 3)
  - Feminist Ethics Evaluations (Box 3)
  - Course Evaluations, 1979 (Box 3)
  - Observer, 1985-1989 (Box 3)
  - Contacts Full Professors Miscellaneous, 1989 (Box 3)
  - AAR, 1971-1976 (Box 3)
  - Abortion Misc., 1970-1978 (Box 3)
  - Berkshire Conference, 1974 (Box 3)
  - Bicentennial and Women, 1976 (Box 3)
  - Black Feminist Organization (Box 3)
  - Boston Bail Project, 1978 (Box 3)
  - B.T.I. Women's Institute (Box 3)
  - Bread and Roses, 1975 (Box 3)
  - Center for Women Scholars, 1979 (Box 3)
  - Chrysalis, 1978-1979 (Box 3)
  - Church History, 1973 (Box 3)
  - Civil Rights, 1973 (Box 3)
  - Communications Network, 1975 (Box 3)
  - Co optation, 1976 (Box 3)
  - Boston Theological Society, 1970-1974 (Box 3)
  - Curtis Brown and Publishers Contacted, 1971-1973 (Box 4)
  - Diaspora, 1973 (Box 4)
  - Drinan, F, 1974 (Box 4)
  - Ella Ellison, 1978 (Box 4)
  - E.S.P., 1972 (Box 4)
  - FBI, 1975 (Box 4)
  - First Church in Cambridge (Radio National Responses), 1973 (Box 4)
  - Grants, 1968-1977 (Box 4)
  - Goodman, Emily, 1974 (Box 4)
  - Spinning Groups, 1980 (Box 4)
  - Guide to Female Studies, 1974 (Box 4)
  - Feminist Studies: Reclaiming Our Own (Box 4)
  - Honorarium, 1972-1973 (Box 4)
  - International Feminist Contacts, 1974-1976 (Box 4)
  - Interviews Julie Melrose, 1978-1979 (Box 4)
  - Ja Shin Do, 1978 (Box 4)
  - Jobs--Future, 1973-1976 (Box 4)
  - Jobs--Old, 1954-1968 (Box 4)
  - Letters of Recommendation (Non-BC), 1972-1979 (Box 4)
  - Mabel and Harriet (Box 4)
  - Burns and Mac Master and Michael B. apt. lease, 1972-1976 (Box 4)
  - Murray, Carol, 1977-1978 (Box 4)
  - Organizations and Periodicals: Dues and Payment, 1972 (Box 4)
  - Parking, 1978 (Box 4)
  - Peacework, 1974 (Box 4)
  - Periodicals: Editors, 1971-1973 (Box 4)
  - Women, Church and the State Persephone Press, 1978-1980 (Box 4)
  - People's Party (Box 4)
  - Photographer Diana Davies (Box 4)
  - Publications Misc. (Box 4)
  - Publications of Mary Daly Short List (Box 4)
  - Speaking Engagements Refused, 1977-1978 (Box 4)
  - Speaking Engagements, 1972-1975 (Box 4)
  - Speaking Engagements Clippings, 1973-1975 (Box 4)
  - Speaking Engagements Correspondence, 1974-1975 (Box 4)
  - Skis (Box 4)
  - Sojourner (Box 4)
  - Speakers Bureaus, 1974-1976 (Box 4)
  - Radcliffe Fellowship Application, 1978 (Box 4)
  - Religious Coalition for Abortion Rights, 1974 (Box 4)
  - Rockefeller Foundation, 1975-1978 (Box 4)
  - De La Quadra, Ann-Katherine, 1987 (Box 4)
  - Refused Speaking Engagements, 1985-1986 (Box 4)
  - NY Speech, 1987 (Box 4)
  - Atlanta Speech at Emory, 1987 (Box 4)
  - University of Kentucky, 1984-1985 (Box 4)
  - Wall Street Journal (Box 4)
  - Winter Solstice Yule Festival (Box 4)
  - W.I.T.C.H., 1986-1988 (Box 4)
  - Video Filmes, 1988 (Box 4)
  - Tamarack and Mountain (Box 4)
  - Vitamins (Box 4)
  - Weatherspoon, Barbara, 1987 (Box 4)
  - The Women's Press Catalogs, 2000 (Box 4)
  - Women's Inst. for Freedom of the Press, 1987 (Box 4)
  - BC Articles, Book Reviews, 1979-2000 (Box 5)
  - BC Th. 527, 1972 (Box 5)
  - BC Courses Th. 950, 1973-1974 (Box 5)
  - Outercourse Manuscript, 1992 (Box 5)
  - Vitae, 1978-1979 (Box 5)
  - Current Vitae (Box 5)
  - Equal Employment Opportunity Case, 1975 (Box 5)
  - Curriculum Vitae, 1972-1977 (Box 5)
  - Th 093, 1973 (Box 5)
  - Women's Liberation and Ethics Th 555, 1974 (Box 5)
  - Course Calendars and Syllabus, 1974-1975 (Box 5)
  - BC Courses, 1974-1975 (Box 5)
  - Th 652, 1975 (Box 5)
  - Th 55401, 1975 (Box 5)
  - Th 55402, 1975 (Box 5)
  - Feminist Ethics I, 1974 (Box 5)
  - Th 093, 1974 (Box 5)
  - Th 955, 1974 (Box 5)
  - BC Spring, 1974 (Box 5)
  - Miscellaneous Loose Documents, 1974-2000 (Box 5)
  - Misc. Notes (Box 5)
  - Ongoing: Business, 1985-1986 (Box 5)
  - BC Women, 1972-1977 (Box 6)
  - BC Women's Center, 1975-1979 (Box 6)
  - BC Women Li-Li Ch'en Case, 1971-1972 (Box 6)
  - BC Research, 1968-1976 (Box 6)
  - BC Salary (and Union), 1966-1980 (Box 6)
  - BC Telephone, 1973 (Box 6)
  - BC Travel, 1974 (Box 6)
  - BC Dept. of Theol. Travel Funding, 1978-1979 (Box 6)
  - BC and La Crosse Harassment, 1982 (Box 6)
  - Harassment, 1974-1982 (Box 6)
  - BC Harassment, 1983-1985 (Box 6)
  - BC Libraries, 1974-1977 (Box 6)
  - BC MA Program (Box 6)
  - BC Parking, 1973-1974 (Box 6)
  - BC Publicity Facilities, 1973-1974 (Box 6)
  - BC Public Relations, 1975 (Box 6)
  - BC General Information, 1973-1975 (Box 6)
  - BC Faculty Service Report, 1974-1975 (Box 6)
  - BC Feminist Lecture Series, 1979-1980 (Box 6)
  - BC Fortin, Ernest, 1970-1973 (Box 6)
  - BC Faculty Caucus, 1974 (Box 6)
  - BC Faculty Publications, 1978-1983 (Box 6)
  - BC PR Faculty Profile, 1978 (Box 6)
  - Boston College Correspondence Theo. Dept., 1975-1976 (Box 6)
  - Chairman Daly, Robert, 1979-1980 (Box 6)
  - Dept. of Theology, 1973-1979 (Box 6)
  - Sagaris (Box 6)
  - Newton Gold, 1975 (Box 6)
  - Radical Philosophers, 1973 (Box 6)
  - SSSR, 1973 (Box 6)
  - Recommendations / Miscellaneous, 1975 (Box 6)
  - Union Graduate School, 1974 (Box 6)
  - Union Theol. Sem. Course Notes, Calendar, Grades - Spring, 1973 (Box 6)
  - Union Theol. Sem. Correspondence, 1971-1972 (Box 6)
  - Yale Committee, 1972-1973 (Box 6)
  - BTI Women Faculty, 1978-1979 (Box 6)
  - BTI Women's Committee Early Documents (Unsorted), 1970-1971 (Box 6)
  - BTI Women, -present, 1974-1980 (Box 6)
  - BC Women's Studies, 1979 (Box 6)
  - BTI Black Studies, 1973-1974 (Box 6)
  - BTI Carol Adams, 1975 (Box 6)
  - BTI Catalogue, 1980 (Box 6)
  - BTI Ethicists, 1973 (Box 6)
  - BTI Newsletter, 1976 (Box 6)
  - BTI Women, 1973-1974 (Box 6)
  - BC Women / Morrison Case, 1971-1974 (Box 6)
  - Archetype - Suffering Woman, 1971 (Box 6)
  - Datebooks, 1976-1980 (Box 6)
  - Androgyny (Box 7)
  - Datebooks, 1977-1990 (Box 7)
  - Syllabus / Spring, 1982 (Box 7)
  - BC - ANTS / Bibliolatry Seminar, 1973-1974 (Box 7)
  - BC - Andover Newton / Janice Raymond, 1973-1975 (Box 7)
  - BC Course Notes - Theology for a Counterculture, 1971 (Box 7)
  - BC - ANTS / Exec. Committee, EPC, 1973-1974 (Box 7)
  - BC - Course Notes, Thomas Aquinas and [illegible] - Spring, 1972 (Box 7)
  - BC - Andover Newton / Manual of Procedures, 1976 (Box 7)
  - BC - Andover Newton / PhD Program Admissions Committee, 1973-1974 (Box 7)
  - BC - Andover Newton PhD, 1973-1980 (Box 7)
  - Application to Full Professorship Dossier Vol. I and II (Box 7)
  - BC Academic Calendars, 1985-1990 (Box 7)
  - Australia - Thomas P. Nelson, 1985 (Box 7)
  - Bloodroot (Box 7)
  - BC Catalog Copy, 1983 (Box 7)
  - Battered Women, 1983-1984 (Box 7)
  - Deming, Barbara - BC Taxes?, 1985 (Box 7)
  - BC Annual Report, 1989 (Box 7)
  - BC Faculty Publications, 1981-1985 (Box 7)
  - BC Annual Updates, 1994-1996 (Box 7)
  - BC R&R / Winter, 1987 (Box 7)
  - Grades for Spring, 1994 (Box 7)
  - BC - Grade Change / Late Grade Form, 1994 (Box 7)
  - Mythic Patterns (Th. 565) / Fall, 1992 (Box 7)
  - Fem. Ethics II Spring, 1993 (Box 7)
  - Mythic Patterns II Spring, 1993 (Box 8)
  - intro Feminist Ethics II Spring, 1993 (Box 8)
  - FE I (Th. 553), 1992 (Box 8)
  - BC Faculty Publications, 1986-1990 (Box 8)
  - BC Leaves of Absence / Benefits, 1986-1997 (Box 8)
  - BC Parking Permit, 1983 (Box 8)
  - Parties (Box 8)
  - BC Salary, 1983-1999 (Box 8)
  - Dietrich, Don, 1993-1994 (Box 8)
  - BC Schedule, 1985-1986 (Box 8)
  - BC University Statutes, 1960-1980 (Box 8)
  - BC Syllabi, 1984-1993 (Box 8)
  - University Status and Documents, 1969-1970 (Box 8)
  - BC Travel, 1984 (Box 8)
  - BC - Vatican, 1985 (Box 8)
  - Cards, 1986-1987 (Box 8)
  - CORSS Bulletin Spring, 1994 (Box 8)
  - Wrist Info, 1993 (Box 8)
  - BC - Ex Corde Ecclesiae, 1993 (Box 8)
  - Salary and Contract Shit, 1993-1994 (Box 8)
  - Dietrich, Don - BC Courses / Master Course List, 1995 (Box 8)
  - BC Book Orders Spring, 1993 (Box 8)
  - Women's Studies, BC, 1993 (Box 8)
  - Speaking Engagements, 1984-1992 (Box 8)
  - Speaking Engagements, 1975-1983 (Box 9)
  - BC - Andover - Newton / Religion and Society, 1972-1978 (Box 9)
  - Religion and Society Crap, 1974 (Box 9)
  - BC Annual Reports, 1981 (Box 9)
  - BC Athletic Facilities, 1973 (Box 9)
  - BC Attacks, 1974 (Box 9)
  - BC Calendar, 1973-1974 (Box 9)
  - BC - Chairman, 1973-1974 (Box 9)
  - BC Committees / Executive Committee, 1971-1975 (Box 9)
  - BC - Andover Newton PhD, 1970-1974 (Box 9)
  - BC Committees / Promotions, 1974-1975 (Box 9)
  - BC Confidentiality, 1974 (Box 9)
  - BC Community Services, Inventory of (Box 9)
  - BC Course Calendars, 1971 (Box 9)
  - BC Courses - Theol. of Paul Tillich, 1969 (Box 9)
  - BC Course Notes - Sophomore, 1969-1970 (Box 9)
  - BC Courses - Women's Revolution, 1971 (Box 9)
  - BC Course Notes - Faith, Revolution and Authority (Box 9)
  - BC Courses - Transcendence in Modern Theology (Box 9)
  - BC Courses - Theology of Hope, 1968-1969 (Box 9)
  - BC Course Notes - Theol. of Human Becoming, 1971 (Box 9)
  - BC Courses - Church Exposé Material (Box 9)
  - BC Course Evaluations (Box 9)
  - BC Course Evaluations II, 1969-1971 (Box 10)
  - Course Critiques - Th 009 H Spring, 1971 (Box 10)
  - Course Critiques - Th 009 3H Fall, 1971 (Box 10)
  - Course Critiques - Th 195 Spring, 1972 (Box 10)
  - Course Critiques - Th 176 Spring, 1972 (Box 10)
  - Course Critiques - Spring, 1971 (Box 10)
  - BC Grading, 1973-1977 (Box 10)
  - Course Critiques - Mythic Patterns of Patriarchy Spring, 1979 (Box 10)
  - Course Critiques - Feminist Ethics II Spring, 1979 (Box 10)
  - Course Evaluations - Intro to FE Fall, 1983 (Box 10)
  - Course Critiques - Intro Feminist Ethics I, 1979 (Box 10)
  - BC Course Evaluation - Fall, 1978 (Box 10)
  - BC Courses, 1976-1977 (Box 10)
  - Ireland, 1954 (Box 10)
  - Ireland Trip, 1987 (Box 10)
  - BC Fight - Heights, 1988 (Box 10)
  - C.V. (Box 10)
  - Full Professor Proceedings, 1974-1975 (Box 10)
  - Protest and Press, 1988-1989 (Box 10)
  - AAUW, 1989-1990 (Box 10)
  - Grant Info, 1989-1990 (Box 10)
  - Sabbatical, 1989-1990 (Box 10)
  - The Witches Return: Patriarchy on Trial, 1989 (Box 10)
  - Friends' Letters, 1992 (Box 10)
  - Forum on Women in Higher Education, 1975 (Box 10)
  - National Writers Union, 1989 (Box 10)
  - Speech in Bologna, Italy, 1991 (Box 10)